Guide to the Sally Hoyt Spofford papers, 1923-1982
Spofford, Sally Hoyt papers, 1923-1982
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sally Hoyt Spofford Papers, 1923-1982
21-18-2374
Sally Hoyt Spofford, 1914-
3.3 cubic ft.
Letters, manuscripts, notes, books, photographs, and drawings
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, notes, manuscripts, and memoranda pertaining to the administration of the Laboratory of Ornithology and her other interests in ornithology; rough drafts of Arthur A. Allen correspondence and writings; Edna Lane's Bird and Flying Squirrel field notes; Christmas newsletters with photographs from Peter Paul Kellogg; and J. Southgate Hoyt field notes, manuscripts, drawings, a draft of his Ph.D. thesis, and photographs, primarily relating to the pileated woodpecker. Also, Arthur Allen slides that match Bird Song records and files relating to the Federation of New York State Bird Clubs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Ornithologist, Administrative Assistant at the Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, notes, manuscripts, and memoranda pertaining to the administration of the Laboratory of Ornithology and her other interests in ornithology; rough drafts of Arthur A. Allen correspondence and writings; Edna Lane's Bird and Flying Squirrel field notes; Christmas newsletters with photographs from Peter Paul Kellogg; and J. Southgate Hoyt field notes, manuscripts, drawings, a draft of his Ph.D. thesis, and photographs, primarily relating to the pileated woodpecker.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Spofford, Sally Hoyt, 1914-; Allen, Arthur A. (Arthur Augustus), 1885-1964; Kellogg, Peter Paul, 1899-1975.; Hoyt, John Southgate Yeaton, 1913-1951.; Cornell University. Laboratory of Ornithology.
Subjects:
Ornithology--Study and teaching.; Bird refuges--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Woodpeckers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Laboratory of Ornithology and Personal Correspondence
Box 1
Series II. Arthur A. Allen Drafts
Box 1
Series III. Southgate Y. Hoyt and Sally Hoyt Spofford Papers
Boxes 1-4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Laboratory of Ornithology and Personal Correspondence
  - Arthur A. Allen, Sept. 1956-Aug. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arthur A. Allen; Peter Paul Kellogg, Sept.-Dec. 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - William C. Dilger, Jan. 1956-Oct. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Erma J. Fisk (Mrs. Bradley Fisk), Dec. 1970-Oct. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Peter Paul Kellogg, May 1954-Nov. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Paul and Byrl Kellogg Christmas Cards, 1945-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - W. Keith Kennedy, Nov. 1969-Mar. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Douglas A. Lancaster, Feb. 1968-Sept. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art Lane, Apr.-May 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lewis F. Pearsall, Sept. 1967-July 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arthur G. Peterson, Feb. 1958-Apr. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Olin Sewell Pettingill, Apr. 1961-Dec. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Olin Sewell Pettingill, Mar. 1964-July 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Scheetz (Mrs. Francis Scheetz), Jan. 1957-Feb. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Charles G. Sibley, Nov. 1953-May 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Lyman K. Stuart, July 1958-Sept. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Charles Sutherland, Apr.-July 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Gustav A. Swanson, July 1959-Aug. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - James Tate, Jr., Apr. 1970-Sept. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fred Kent Truslow, Apr.-Aug. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, Jan. 1957-Dec. 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, Jan.-Dec. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, Jan. 1964-Dec. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Search for Director, Mar.-Oct. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Lab Job, May 1967-Dec. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Response to J. Southgate Y. Hoyt Broadcast, Mar. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Income/Expense Statements and Related Material, July 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Accounting Notes, Letters, Nov. 1958-Jan. 1959 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper Clippings, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Series II. Arthur A. Allen Drafts
  - Handwritten Letters, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Drafts, #1, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Drafts, #2, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Series III. J. Southgate Y. Hoyt and Sally Hoyt Spofford Papers
  - Draft of Ph.D. Thesis, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Photos of Pileated Woodpecker, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Photos of Pileated Woodpecker Development, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Photos and Negatives, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Articles, Reprints, Publications, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Carbon Manuscript-Published, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Elsa Guerdrum Allen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - New York Upstate Birds - Hoyt and Pettingill - Early Drafts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Pileated Woodpecker Material, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Pileated Woodpecker, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Bird Study Class (Campus Club), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Key to North America Bird Eggs - Manuscript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Women's Committee - International Ornithological Congress (IOC), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - (IOC), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Newspaper Clippings, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Laboratory of Ornithology Correspondence, S. H. Spofford, 1963-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Ornithology and Lab Correspondence, 1956-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nature Study Course, Cold Spring Harbor - Long Island Biological Association, 1942-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Correspondence, 1947-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
  - Ornithology Class Quizzes, Reports (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lab Matters (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Laboratory Directorship, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re Pileated Woodpecker, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Natural History, 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Extension Releases, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence re Sightings, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Thesis, Charts, Drawings (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Civil Service, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Published Manuscripts, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - "Edna Lane's Bird and Flying Squirrel Notes", 1939-1956 (Box 2, Folder 20-23)
  - A. A. Allen Lecture Notes (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - J. S. Y. Hoyt Thesis, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hoyt Notes and Observation Records, 1939-1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Cyclops Material (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ornithology Synopsis and Key to Birds (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Pileated Woodpecker Field Notes, Hoyt, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - The Migration of Birds, S. Y. Hoyt, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Drawings - Pileated Woodpecker Anatomy, J. Southgate Hoyt (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Notes on 1941 Pileated Woodpecker Nest, Phloeo, 1941-1952 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Manuscripts - Hoyt (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Student Photographs in South's Course, Hoyt (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Map, Pileated Woodpecker Locations, Hoyt, 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Conservation 131 Lecture Notes, Hoyt, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pileated Woodpecker Correspondence, 1938-1949 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Birds of the World by A. A. Allen; Lecture and Laboratory Notes, Ornithology 126, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Annual Bird Lists, 1933-1939 (Box 3)
  - Photograph Album (Box 3)
  - Photograph Album (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Field List of Birds, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Example of Recent American Bird Art" by Harry Harris, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Bird Life in America" Series II (2 complete sets) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory of Ornithology History by Spofford (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "The Southgate Y. Hoyt Dispatch", ca. 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Journal Notes (loose) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Scripts for Lectures (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Old Rough Drafts, Minutes (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Laboratory Information, Brochures, Flyers, etc. (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Laboratory Financial Statements, etc., 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Laboratory Financial Statements, etc., 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Daybooks, 1957-1966 (Box 4)
  - Laboratory of Ornithology Newsletters and Meeting Minutes, 1956-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes a note to Charles Smith from "Sally and Spoff" from 1991
  - Laboratory of Ornithology Newsletters, 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Federation Bird Group, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Federation of New York State Bird Clubs (1), 1954-1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Federation of New York State Bird Clubs (2), 1954-1961 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - State Bird Book, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Arthur Allen's discarded conservation lecture notes, c. 1936-1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bird sighting notes, 1938-1941 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Includes an hand-drawn map of Sapsucker Woods with notations of bird sighting from 1935-1941
  - The 1957-1958 New Zealand-Australia Expedition of the Laboratory of Ornithology, 1958 (Box 5, Volume 1)
  - Arthur Allen Slides that Match Bird Song Records, undated (Box 6)
  - Arthur Allen slides that match Bird Song Records; other Arthur Allen slides, undated (Box 7)
  - Negatives of Pileated Woodpecker work by J.S. Hoyt; other bird species; copies of famous prints, 1930s-1950 (Box 8)
  - Pileated film from Man in Ohio, 1959; F-601 (Box 8)